Guide to the Edwin J. Beinecke Collection of Robert Louis Stevenson
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Research Files, 1877-1970; Series IV; 3.75; (9 boxes)
  - Volume I
    - Documents
      - Bank checks for Manufacturers Trust Company, 1940 December (Box 72, Folder 1671)
      - Invoices, 1940 (Box 72, Folder 1672)
      - Notes relating to Stevenson material by Gertrude Hill, undated (Box 72, Folder 1673-1678)
      - Miscellaneous, 1941, undated (Box 72, Folder 1679)
  - Volume II
    - General Correspondence
      - Albatross & Tauchnitz, 1938-1939 (Box 72, Folder 1680)
      - Alexander, William F., 1940 June 18 (Box 72, Folder 1681)
      - "C" General, 1932 (Box 72, Folder 1682)
      - Cassell & Company, 1933, 1939 (Box 72, Folder 1683)
        Includes third party correspondence
      - Chatto & Windus (Firm), 1938-1939 (Box 72, Folder 1684)
      - D. Appleton-Century Company, 1933 November 8 (Box 72, Folder 1685)
      - Electrical Testing Laboratories, 1939-1940 (Box 72, Folder 1686)
      - Flanagan, John, 1940 March 15 (Box 72, Folder 1687)
      - "H" General, 1931-1934 (Box 72, Folder 1688)
      - Harvard University, 1932, 1934 (Box 72, Folder 1689)
      - Hills, Gertrude, 1938 November 8 (Box 72, Folder 1690)
      - Institute of Paper Chemistry (Appleton, Wis.), 1939 (Box 72, Folder 1691)
      - James F. Drake, Inc., 1941 March 19 (Box 72, Folder 1692)
      - John Crerar Library, 1940 March (Box 72, Folder 1693)
      - John Howell Books (San Francisco, Calif.), 1932 May 19 (Box 72, Folder 1694)
      - Library of Congress, 1923-1940 (Box 72, Folder 1695)
      - Longmans, Green, and Co., 1939-1940 (Box 72, Folder 1696)
      - "R" General, 1938, 1940 (Box 72, Folder 1697)
      - R. &. R. Clark (Firm), 1939 June 9 (Box 72, Folder 1698)
      - T. & A. Constable Ltd., 1936-1939 (Box 73, Folder 1699-1700)
      - Thomas J. Gannon, Inc., 1938 July 11 (Box 73, Folder 1701)
      - Walter T. Spencer, 1932 February 19 (Box 73, Folder 1702)
      - Correspondence relating to Valerian Gribayedoff's pen-and-ink portrait of Stevenson, 1939 (Box 73, Folder 1703)
      - Correspondence and documents relating to Robert Louis Stevenson's contributions to the Monterey Californian, 1939-1940, undated (Box 73, Folder 1704)
    - George S. Hellman Correspondence
      - Burgess, Gelett, 1924 November 25 (Box 73, Folder 1705)
      - Century Illustrated Monthly Magazine, 1925 February 11 (Box 73, Folder 1706)
      - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1925 (Box 73, Folder 1707)
      - Colvin, Sidney, Sir, 1922-1923 (Box 73, Folder 1708)
      - Hamilton, Clayton Meeker, 1922-1925 (Box 73, Folder 1709)
      - Little, Brown and Company, 1925 April (Box 73, Folder 1710)
      - Low, Will H[icok], 1924 November 21 (Box 73, Folder 1711)
      - Macmillan Company, 1925 (Box 73, Folder 1712)
      - The New Leader, 1923 January 29 (Box 73, Folder 1713)
      - New York Globe, 1923 (Box 73, Folder 1714)
      - New York Tribune, 1922-1924 (Box 73, Folder 1715)
      - Osbourne, Lloyd, 1917-1925 (Box 73, Folder 1716)
      - Steuart, John A., 1923-1925 (Box 73, Folder 1717)
      - The Times, 1923 (Box 73, Folder 1718)
      - Others, 1923-1925, undated (Box 73, Folder 1719-1720)
    - Other Correspondence
      - Century Company to Roberts Brothers (Boston, Mass.), 1883 (Box 73, Folder 1721)
      - Maggs Bros. to T. J. Gannon, 1923 May 10 (Box 73, Folder 1722)
      - Stevenson, Fanny Van de Grift to [Dora Norton] Williams, undated (Box 73, Folder 1723)
        Copy of letter
      - Stevenson, Robert Louis to "Mrs. Ehrich", undated (Box 73, Folder 1724)
    - Documents
      - Description of Charles Baxter's copy of "The Wrong Box", undated (Box 73, Folder 1725)
      - Short description to Edwin J. Beinecke's Stevenson Collection, undated (Box 73, Folder 1726)
      - Calculations with notes on verso, undated (Box 73, Folder 1727)
      - Transcript of Letter to [Dora Norton] Williams from Mrs. Robert Louis Stevenson, undated (Box 73, Folder 1728)
      - Article on Stevenson in El Paso Times, 1935 January 6
      - Article on Stevenson in New York Times Book Review, 1941 January 12
      - Issue of The Collector including article on Stevenson and Edwin J. Beinecke's handwriting book (2 copies), 1941 February (Box 73, Folder 1729)
      - List of books advertised in Stevenson's The Wrecker, 1892 edition, undated (Box 73, Folder 1730)
      - "R.L. Stevenson and Psychic Research" chapter from I Came, I Saw, undated (Box 73, Folder 1731)
      - List of American pirated Stevenson works, undated (Box 73, Folder 1732)
      - List of "American Notes Variants" from B. W. Cutler's manuscript of pirated first edition, undated (Box 73, Folder 1733)
      - Clipping advertising Stevenson's serial story, "Black Arrow", undated (Box 73, Folder 1734)
      - Index card with inscription: "Massey, for photostats of Henderson Weekly, Black Arrow, and to NY Public", undated (Box 73, Folder 1735)
      - Library cards for photostats of American syndication, undated (Box 73, Folder 1736)
      - Article by John G. Rowe about "Black Arrow", undated (Box 73, Folder 1737)
      - Note on Jekyll and Hyde manuscript of Sullivan and Mansfield, undated (Box 73, Folder 1738)
      - Clipping from sale of Stevenson auction, Oct. 30-31 and Nov. 1, 1940, with notes (Box 73, Folder 1739)
      - Note: "Dynamiter-see Soupmares", undated (Box 73, Folder 1740)
      - Transcript of The Life of Mrs. Robt. L. Stevenson, by Nellie Van de Grift Sanchez. Quotes a letter from Paul Hoflich, a German traveler who sailed aboard the "Equator" with RLS and Mrs. RLS, also quoting Lloyd Osbourne. With chorus, probably written by RLS, that was sung while on the "Equator", undated (Box 73, Folder 1741)
      - Transcription and description of "Ode to a Nightingale," a poem by Richard Barnefield. Point of interest in poem's reference to King Pandion, Greek mythical king, undated (Box 73, Folder 1742)
      - Card which discusses Dean Austin Macaire and efforts to buy his works, undated (Box 73, Folder 1743)
      - Entry for a card catalog on full sheet of paper for poem "Lost Youth" by RLS, which appeared in McClure's in March, 1896, undated (Box 73, Folder 1744)
      - Similar entry for "Master of Ballantrae", "Author's Edition", w/ note typed at top, "From Gannon's Prideaux. Notes in pencil. Search by LC Copyright Office on Master of Ballantrae sent to Mrs. Hills, 1939 March 6 (Box 73, Folder 1745)
      - Souce for an RLS metaphor: "mouse in a cat's ear"-bibliographical information on a poem by John Skelton, Webster's Dictionary, undated (Box 73, Folder 1746)
      - Silver photostat of E.V. Lucas' handwriting, undated (Box 73, Folder 1747)
      - Description of the 1882 edition of New Arabian Nights, undated (Box 73, Folder 1748)
      - Notecard on "Nicholson, John" directing the reader to "see under B; Library of Congress letter" of Feb. 18, 1932, undated (Box 73, Folder 1749)
      - Note "Pav. On Sinks see under I- Letter of Library of Congress April 23, 1935", undated (Box 73, Folder 1750)
      - Statement sent to Mrs. Hills from Zark Pritchard regarding RLS. Notes in pencil on back saying that Pritchard's account of RLS is a "mirage", undated (Box 73, Folder 1751)
      - Discussion of Stevenson's "Requiem", undated (Box 73, Folder 1752)
      - Note on Silverado Squatters from the Ashley Catalog, undated (Box 73, Folder 1753)
      - Note: "Roberts of Boston, copyrights-see L. of C. let(ter) Feb. 12, 1932 under B", undated (Box 73, Folder 1754)
      - Note from McClure's autobiography about Stevenson's letters from the South Seas, undated (Box 73, Folder 1755)
      - Notes on two cards relating to Saint-Gaudens' plaster reduction of Stevenson, 1905, undated (Box 73, Folder 1756)
      - Biographical statement on R.A.M. Stevenson, undated (Box 73, Folder 1757)
      - Notes on manuscript for The Squaw Man, undated (Box 73, Folder 1758)
      - List of Stevenson sets in Edwin J. Beinecke's collection, undated (Box 73, Folder 1759)
      - Bibliographical note on an early unrecorded American printing of Treasure Island, undated (Box 73, Folder 1760)
      - Two photos of pages from letters from the South Seas, undated (Box 73, Folder 1761)
      - Information on first edition of Treasure Island, undated (Box 73, Folder 1762)
      - Page from Bertram Rota catalogue, "First Editions" section, undated (Box 73, Folder 1763)
      - Notes on The Wrecker, undated (Box 74, Folder 1764)
      - Notes on printings of The Weir of Hermiston, 1932 November 22 (Box 74, Folder 1765)
      - Memorandum on printings of The Weir of Hermiston and Widener Library, undated (Box 74, Folder 1766)
      - Description of collation of copyright issue of Weir, undated (Box 74, Folder 1767)
      - Information on Weir copyright issue, undated (Box 74, Folder 1768)
      - Prideaux's bibliographical information on Weir, undated (Box 74, Folder 1769)
      - Information pertaining to The Wrecker, undated (Box 74, Folder 1770)
      - Note card on RLS collector Henry J. Lockhart, Jr., undated (Box 74, Folder 1771)
      - Torn fragment making reference to Stone and Kimball and Weir, undated (Box 74, Folder 1772)
      - Copies of Chatto & Windus records, undated (Box 74, Folder 1773)
      - Material relating to "A Child's Garden of Verses", undated (Box 74, Folder 1774)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 74, Folder 1775)
      - Top of box with notes, undated (Box 74, Folder 1776)
      - "The Stevenson Controversy," with annotation by George S. Hellman, undated (Box 74, Folder 1777)
      - "A Note on 'The Castaways of Soledad'" by George S. Hellman, undated (Box 74, Folder 1778)
      - "'Cue' Stories of Stevenson" by George S. Hellman, undated (Box 74, Folder 1779)
      - "Transcripts of various hitherto unpublished prose pieces...", undated (Box 74, Folder 1780-1791)
      - Misellaneous proof sheets, 1916, undated (Box 74, Folder 1792-1793)
  - Volume III
    - Letters to Sidney Colvin
      - Broadbent, Henry, 1921 December 26 (Box 74, Folder 1794)
      - [Cantuar, Randall?], 1911 January 4 (Box 74, Folder 1795)
      - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1912, 1921 (Box 74, Folder 1796)
      - Gosse, Edmund, 1923 February 19 (Box 74, Folder 1797)
      - Gourlay Engraving Company, 1924 June 3 (Box 74, Folder 1798)
      - [Hamerton, Philip Gilbert?], undated (Box 74, Folder 1799)
      - Hamilton, Clayton Meeker, 1923 (Box 74, Folder 1800)
      - Morris, Harrison S. (Harrison Smith), 1922 November 10 (Box 74, Folder 1801)
      - Robert Louis Stevenson Club, 1920-1922 (Box 74, Folder 1802)
      - [Stone & Kimball?], [18]95 August 7 (Box 74, Folder 1803)
      - Warren, Herbert, 1911 April 10 (Box 74, Folder 1804)
      - White, W[illiam] A[llen], 1911 December 1 (Box 74, Folder 1805)
    - Other Correspondence
      - Balfour, Graham to unidentified (transcript) stating that Stevenson could have owned a stick, undated (Box 74, Folder 1806)
      - [Morrison, J. Cotter?] to Mrs Sitwell (transcript), undated (Box 74, Folder 1807-1808)
      - Osbourne, Lloyd to Graham Balfour (transcript) stating that Stevenson did not own a stick, undated (Box 74, Folder 1809)
      - Copies of letters by Robert Louis Stevenson, undated (Box 74, Folder 1810-1811)
    - Documents
      - "Reminiscences of Coliston Manse", undated (Box 74, Folder 1812)
      - Manuscript with Edwin J. Beinecke's bibliographical notes, undated (Box 74, Folder 1813)
      - "Notes of Childhood," with notes regarding its use by Graham Balfour, undated (Box 74, Folder 1814)
      - "Early Memories", undated (Box 74, Folder 1815)
      - RLS Autobiographical Passages copied from notebooks, with notes relating to Balfour, signed "EJB 11/19/29", 1929 November 19 (Box 74, Folder 1816)
      - Notes relating to copies of letters by Henry James, undated (Box 74, Folder 1817)
      - Envelopes, undated (Box 74, Folder 1818)
      - "Robert Louis Stevenson at Hampstead" by Sidney Colvin (fragment), [19]30 February 2 (Box 74, Folder 1819)
      - Sidney Colvin's typescript intended for Recollections (1922), [19]30 February 2 (Box 74, Folder 1820)
      - "A Dialogue of Research Concerning the True in Art Poetry and Science...", undated (Box 74, Folder 1821)
      - Note, undated (Box 74, Folder 1822)
      - "New Letters of Robert Louis Stevenson," manuscript, with note, 1923 June (Box 74, Folder 1823)
  - Volume IV
    - General Correspondence
      - Albatross & Tauchnitz, 1938 August (Box 75, Folder 1824)
      - Lofties, Cecilia, 1938 March 19 (Box 75, Folder 1825)
      - Miller, [Haswell?], 1937 August 27 (Box 75, Folder 1826)
      - Robert Louis Stevenson School, 1935 June 19 (Box 75, Folder 1827)
      - Seitz, Don C[arlos?], 1932 June 8 (Box 75, Folder 1828)
      - Walter T. Spencer, 1930 August 12 (Box 75, Folder 1829)
      - Unidentified, 1936 May 8 (Box 75, Folder 1830)
    - Letters to Sidney Colvin
      - Alexander, E. Lennox, 1911 October 16 (Box 75, Folder 1831)
      - Baildon, H. Bellyse (Henry Bellyse), 1898 March 19 (Box 75, Folder 1832)
      - Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew), [1898?] October 20 (Box 75, Folder 1833)
      - Baxter, Charles, 1896, 1899 (Box 75, Folder 1834)
      - "C" General, 1905, 1922 (Box 75, Folder 1835)
      - Caw, J. L. (James Lewis), Sir, 1899 October 3 (Box 75, Folder 1836)
      - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1922 April 21 (Box 75, Folder 1837)
      - Dickson, William K[irk?], 1920 May 1 (Box 75, Folder 1838)
      - [Dunedin, A. Graham Murray?], 1896 March 15 (Box 75, Folder 1839)
      - Gilder, Richard Watson, 1896 June 25 (Box 75, Folder 1840)
      - Grappe, Georges, 1902 September 10 (Box 75, Folder 1841)
      - Hamilton, John D., 1901, [19]18 (Box 75, Folder 1842)
      - Ireland, F. G., 1896 January 24 (Box 75, Folder 1843)
        Includes copy of letter to Ireland, dated 1883, from Robert Louis Stevenson
      - Jenkin, ----, [1877] December 29 (Box 75, Folder 1844)
      - Lang, Andrew, undated (Box 75, Folder 1845)
      - Moors, H. J., 1924 May 6 (Box 75, Folder 1846)
      - Osbourne, Lloyd, 1898 February 15 (Box 75, Folder 1847)
      - Robert Louis Stevenson Club, 1921-1922 (Box 75, Folder 1848)
        Includes letter from Auguste Rodin
      - Rodin, Auguste, 1910 (Box 75, Folder 1849)
      - [Runciman, James?], 1880 February 5 (Box 75, Folder 1850)
      - "S" General, 1896, 1922 (Box 75, Folder 1851)
      - Stevenson, Charles A., undated (Box 75, Folder 1852)
      - Strong, J. D. [(Joseph Dwight)?], 1879 October 11 (Box 75, Folder 1853)
      - Thompson, Sidney, [1901?] May 3 (Box 75, Folder 1854)
      - Welling, Beatrice W[inifred?], 1922 (Box 75, Folder 1855)
        Includes photographs and printed ephemera
      - Wray, W. Fitzwater, 1901 March 8 (Box 75, Folder 1856)
    - Letters to George S. Hellman
      - Allen, Maryland, 1925 October 11 (Box 75, Folder 1857)
      - Cabell, James Branch, 1925 October 12 (Box 75, Folder 1858)
      - Hamilton, Clayton [Meeker], 1917 April 13 (Box 75, Folder 1859)
      - Harvard University Library, 1923 January (Box 75, Folder 1860)
      - Low, Will H[icok], 1924 November 21 (Box 75, Folder 1861)
      - Masson, Rosaline [Orme], 1924 August 6 (Box 75, Folder 1862)
      - O'Brien, Frederick, 1922 November 28 (Box 75, Folder 1863)
      - Osbourne, Katharine Durham to [Hellman] (excerpt), undated (Box 75, Folder 1864)
      - Osbourne, Lloyd, 1925 April 14 (Box 75, Folder 1865)
      - Peabody, J. S., 1915-1916 (Box 75, Folder 1866)
    - Other Correspondence
      - Baxter, Charles to John Lane, 1899 August 1 (Box 75, Folder 1867)
      - Davis, Richard Harding to [Robert Louis] Stevenson, 1887 October 18 (Box 75, Folder 1868)
      - Dewar, James, Sir to unidentified, undated (Box 75, Folder 1869)
      - [Field], Isobel to John Howell, 1911, undated (Box 75, Folder 1870)
      - Heinemann (Firm) to Charles Baxter, 1899 January 27 (Box 75, Folder 1871)
      - Irwin, Wallace Irwin to James King Steele, 1925 June 11 (Box 75, Folder 1872)
      - [Jenkins, Ann] to Mrs. Stevenson, 1878 January 2 (Box 75, Folder 1873)
      - Low, Will H[icok] to Katharine D[urham] Osborne, 1915 April 25 (Box 75, Folder 1874)
      - MacLeod, Donald to unidentified, [1880] February 4 (Box 75, Folder 1875)
      - Middleton, L. M. to Vincent Starrett, 1919 April 15 (Box 75, Folder 1876)
      - Moore, George to [Edmund] Gosse, [1913] November 15 (Box 75, Folder 1877)
      - Ormond, G. W. T. to unidentified, 1900 January 31 (Box 75, Folder 1878)
      - Osbourne, Katharine Durham to Mr. Howell, 1922, undated (Box 75, Folder 1879)
      - Osbourne, Lloyd to "Louise", 1899 April 15 (Box 75, Folder 1880)
      - Osbourne, Lloyd to Thomas Hutchinson, [1896 April 25] (Box 75, Folder 1881)
      - Osbourne, R. P. to John Howell, 1922 October 6 (Box 75, Folder 1882)
      - Roberts Brothers to Chatto & Windus (Firm), [18]83 April 18 (Box 75, Folder 1883)
      - Saintsbury, George to W. H. P[ollock], [1886?] January 30 (Box 75, Folder 1884)
      - Stevenson, Alan (uncle) to "Tom" Stevenson (father), n.y. November 26 (Box 75, Folder 1885)
      - Stevenson, George A. McGregor to Robert Louis Stevenson, 1893 March 23 (Box 75, Folder 1886)
      - Stoddard, [Charles] Warren to Bliss Carman (transcript), undated (Box 75, Folder 1887)
      - Unidentified, 1880, 1938 (Box 75, Folder 1888)
    - Documents
      - "At the Stevenson Fountain": copy of poem and transcript from Wallace Irwin, undated (Box 75, Folder 1889)
      - Bibliographical note in pen & ink by Edwin J. Beinecke, undated (Box 75, Folder 1890)
      - Envelopes, 1899, undated (Box 75, Folder 1891)
      - Printed ephemera, undated (Box 75, Folder 1892)
  - Volume V
    - General Correspondence
      - B. F. Stevens & Brown, Ltd., 1937 (Box 75, Folder 1893)
      - Elkin Mathews Ltd., 1939 (Box 75, Folder 1894)
    - Other Correspondence
      - Stevenson, Robert Louis to Mr. Crocket (transcript), undated (Box 75, Folder 1895)
    - Documents
      - Article by Mrs. Bourke Cochran on her recollections of RLS, undated (Box 75, Folder 1896)
      - Copy of "The Monthly Letter of the Limited Editions Club," no. 114, 1938 November (Box 75, Folder 1897)
      - Advertisement for the Colophon, 1939 (Box 75, Folder 1898)
      - Notes, typescript, undated (Box 75, Folder 1899)
      - Article by Lord Guthrie on RLS in Juridical Review, 1919 July (Box 75, Folder 1900)
      - Display cards from exhibit at Grolier Clu., undated (Box 75, Folder 1901)
      - "The Edwin J. Beinecke Collection of Robert Louis Stevenson" by Gertrude Hills, 1939 (Box 75, Folder 1902)
      - Note on envelope to GH from EJB congratulating her on a grand job for the book and asking her to have it bound, undated (Box 75, Folder 1903)
      - Two bookplates and three RLS poems, undated (Box 75, Folder 1904)
      - Copy of poem "R.L.S." by A. E. Housman, 1941 March 8 (Box 76, Folder 1905)
      - Sent to EJB by V. Starrett, 1934, with note to EJB to send a reply, undated (Box 76, Folder 1906)
      - Copy of Stevensoniana auctioned, undated (Box 76, Folder 1907)
      - Catalogue of letters from Mrs. Robert Louis Stevenson to [Dora Norton] Williams, bought by EJB from John Howell, undated (Box 76, Folder 1908)
      - Catalogue of letters to Mr. and Mrs. RLS from Virgil and Dora [Norton] Williams, for sale by Howell, undated (Box 76, Folder 1909)
      - Overbrook Press Checklist 1934-1940., 1940 September 1 (Box 76, Folder 1910)
      - Publicity for An Inland Voyage, sent out June 1937, book published in January 1939, undated (Box 76, Folder 1911)
      - Chapter entitled, "To. Mr. Robert Louis Stevenson", from "Letters to Living Authors" by John A. Stewart, undated (Box 76, Folder 1912)
      - Postcard advertisement from John Howell Books for the Monterey Peninsula, [1941] (Box 76, Folder 1913)
      - Copy of "The Little Bronze Ship" by W.O. McGeehan, with bibliographical note, undated (Box 76, Folder 1914)
      - Catalogue of Stevensoniana offered by Gannon, 1932 May 23 (Box 76, Folder 1915)
      - Two bookplates, undated (Box 76, Folder 1916)
      - Transcript of "To Robert Louis Stevenson" by Porter, from "The Lark" of June, 1895, sent to EJB by Flodden W. Heron, undated (Box 76, Folder 1917)
      - Note about poem by Bruce Porter published in "The Lark", undated (Box 76, Folder 1918)
      - Envelope to [Dora Norton] Williams from Bruce Porter, 1914 November 25 (Box 76, Folder 1919)
      - Hamill & Barker catalogue of Stevenson manuscripts, with notes to Edwin J. Beinecke from Gertrude Hills, undated (Box 76, Folder 1920)
      - Menu from the Blue Fox Cafe, San Francisco, 1940 April 5 (Box 76, Folder 1921)
      - Articles by Lewis J. Moorman, 1934-1935 (Box 76, Folder 1922)
      - "In Memoriam, RLS". Dec. 30, 1894. Supplement to The Bookman, Vol. 1, #1, 1895 (Box 76, Folder 1923)
      - Publicity for Henry Young & Sons' Ltd. "Robert Louis Stevenson: Ennobling Thoughts", 1914 (Box 76, Folder 1924)
      - Prospectus for a "new limited edition" of the works of RLS called the Pentland edition, issued by Cassel & Co., undated (Box 76, Folder 1925)
      - Printed ephemera relating to the Monterey Peninsula, undated (Box 76, Folder 1926)
      - Advertisement for Cashel Byron's Profession inside, undated (Box 76, Folder 1927)
      - Winter program of the Robert Louis Stevenson Club, London Branch, 1924-1925 (Box 76, Folder 1928)
      - Two poems to Robert Louis Stevenson, typescript, undated (Box 76, Folder 1929)
      - Copy of marriage papers for Joseph Strong and Isabelle Stewart Osbourne, August 9, 1879, Monterey, undated (Box 76, Folder 1930)
      - List of names, undated (Box 76, Folder 1931)
      - "A Hobby Venture of Trovillion Private Press" checklist, 1930 (Box 76, Folder 1932)
      - Folder for "Edifying Letters of the Rutherford Family", with auction folder from the Anderson Auction Co., undated (Box 76, Folder 1933)
  - Volume VI
    - General Correspondence
      - Abbott-Jett, Aimee, 1934 July 20 (Box 76, Folder 1934)
      - Alexander, William F., 1940 (Box 76, Folder 1935)
      - Ashbee, C. R. [(Charles Robert)?], 1932, 1938 (Box 76, Folder 1936)
      - Bassett, Henry L., 1940-1941 (Box 76, Folder 1937)
      - "C" General, 1933-1935 (Box 76, Folder 1938)
      - Claxton, A. E., 1937-1939 (Box 76, Folder 1939)
      - Giles, J. A., 1935-1936 (Box 76, Folder 1940)
      - Griscom, Acton, 1939 September 9 (Box 76, Folder 1941)
      - Grolier Club, 1941 October 6 (Box 76, Folder 1942)
      - Hamilton, Clayton Meeker, 1938 (Box 76, Folder 1943)
      - Heron, Flodden W., 1932 (Box 76, Folder 1944)
      - Hills, Gertrude, 1940-1941 (Box 76, Folder 1945)
      - Ichikawa, Sanki, 1936-1940 (Box 76, Folder 1946)
      - John Howell Books, 1935-1941, undated (Box 76, Folder 1947)
      - Marshall Field & Company, 1939 (Box 76, Folder 1948)
      - McGuire, G. F., 1932 November 4 (Box 76, Folder 1949)
      - Mountain House Press, 1933 August 31 (Box 76, Folder 1950)
      - Mulligan, Kathleen, 1938 April 4 (Box 76, Folder 1951)
      - Osborne, C. Glidden, 1936-1938 (Box 76, Folder 1952)
      - Parke-Bernet Galleries, 1941 October 2 (Box 76, Folder 1953)
        Includes third-party correspondence with Austin Strong
      - Robert Louis Stevenson Club, 1938 November (Box 76, Folder 1954)
      - Robert Louis Stevenson Society, 1938 August 22 (Box 76, Folder 1955)
      - State Library of New South Wales. Mitchell Library, 1936 (Box 76, Folder 1956)
    - Other Correspondence
      - Ashbee, C. R. (Charles Robert) to [Frank Marcham], 1932 May 20 (Box 76, Folder 1957)
      - Robert Louis Stevenson Club to others, 1925, 1933 (Box 76, Folder 1958)
      - Robert Louis Stevenson Memorial Committee to Charles Fairchild, 1896, 1898 (Box 76, Folder 1959)
    - Documents
      - Bibliographical note on Henry Lawrence Bassett, undated (Box 76, Folder 1960)